A Guide to the John K. Martin Records, 1777-1907
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
John K. Martin Records 1777-1907
Library of Virginia
12
18 cubic feet
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles M. Wallace, Jr. of Richmond on 1 November 1912. Originally accessioned on 16 January 1913.
Biographical Information
John K. Martin was born in New Jersey in 1817 and moved to Richmond around 1837. He served as the United States mail agent from 1839 to 1847 and became involved in Democratic Party politics around that time. This political association cost Martin his position as mail agent with the election of Millard Fillmore, a Whig Party member. Martin then developed a legal practice as a pension and claims agent for military veterans. At this time Martin also speculated in western lands to make extra money.
On 27 June 1843 John K. Martin married Elizabeth Howell, daughter of Michael Howell of Richmond, at Centerary Church in Richmond. Martin died on 5 September 1883 in Richmond.
Scope and Content
Records, 1777-1907, of John K. Martin, a pension agent for military veterans of the Revolutionary War, Chesapeake-Leopard Affair, War of 1812, Indian Wars, Mexican War, Civil War. The records contain pension claim files for individual veterans and their spouses relating to their military service. The pension claim files principally consist of correspondence and notes concerning land warrants and military service, but there are also wills, deeds, and even Bible records and genealogical notes proving linkeage of an heir to the veteran or land ownership. Correspondence within the pension files is between Martin, other pension agents and the pension office in Washington, D.C., and veterans and their family members.
This collection also contains Martin's business correspondence, personal correspondence for both Martin and his father in-law Michael Howell, financial files including receipts and account books, Martin's files while serving as an administrator of the estate of Elijah Brown (1781-1850), military files and discharge papers, deeds and plats, publications, Martin's notes, and envelopes which were removed from their respective correspondence at a previous time.
Arrangement
Arranged into the following ten series: I. Pension Files, 1777-1883 and n.d., II. Business Correspondence, 1832-1883 and n.d., III. Personal Correspondence, 1826-1907 and n.d., IV. Financial Files and Volumes, 1815-1882 and n.d., V. Administrator's Files, 1816-1858, VI. Military Files, 1775-1781, 1820-1857 and n.d., VII. Deeds and Plats, 1782-1881 and n.d., VIII. Publications, ca. 1850-1871, IX. Notes, ca. 1840-ca. 1882, X. Envelopes, n.d.
Contents List
- Pension Files, 1777-1883 and n.d., 10.62 cubic feet. (Boxes 1-24)
  Pension files, 1777-1883 and n.d., principally consisting of correspondence, notes, deeds, wills, Bible records, genealogical notes, and other documentation relating to claimants' military services in the Revolutionary War, Chesapeake-Leopard Affair, the War of 1812, Native American Wars including the Sioux Uprising, Black Hawk War, and Seminole Wars, the Mexican War, and the American Civil War. A typical file contains correspondence with the claimant, documentation concerning the nature and length of military service, proof of relationship to the individual performing the service (if deceased), and drafts and correspondence with various Federal government agencies concerning pensions and bounty lands. There are also files for unidentified claimants and claimants of unidentified wars. Volumes containing registers of action and notes on pension claims, 1848-1882, are also found within this series.
  Arranged chronologically by subseries (war) with claimants of unidentified wars and registers of action on claims filed as individual subseries at the end of the series: A. Revolutionary War, B. Chesapeake- Leopard Affair, C. War of 1812, D. Native American Wars, E. Mexican War, F. Civil War, G. Unidentified Wars, H. Registers of Action on Claims.
  - Revolutionary War, 1777-1883 and n.d., 2.25 cubic feet. (Boxes 1-5)
    Pension files, 1777-1883 and n.d., for claimants with military service during the Revolutionary War.
    Folders are arranged alphabetically by veteran's surname with individual items within each folder arranged chronologically.
    - Revolutionary War - A (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Alexander, Morgan, 1876 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Allen, Edward, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Allen, Thomas, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Anderson, David, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Anderson, James, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Anderson, Richard C., 1777-1783 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Angell, William, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Archer, Richard, 1784 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Argerbright, George, 1852-1857 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Armstead, Thomas, 1818 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Armstrong, James, 1852, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Arnold, Lindsey, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Atkinson, Amos, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Avery, William Haley, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary War - Bailey-Baylor (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bailey, William, 1837, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Banks, John, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Banks, John, 1854-1858 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bankston, Andrew, 1850-1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Barnes, John, 1832, 1871-1874 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Barnes, Teter, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Barnett, James, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Barron, Richard, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bates, Fleming, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bates, James, 1832, 1851-1852 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Baylor, George, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary War - Beall-Branch (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Beall, Isaac, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Beasley, Cornelius, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bedinger, George, 1854, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Beeson, Edward, 1853-1854 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Berry, George, 1873, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Berry, Thomas, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Biggs, Benjamin, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Blackwell, Joseph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Blair, John, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Blanch, Ezekiel, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Blankhead, James, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bohannan, Ambrose, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bonnewall, Thomas, 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bowman, Abraham, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bowman, James, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Bowman, Mackness, 1843-1857 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Brady, William, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Branch, Thomas, 1845-1860 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary War - Brewer-Butler (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brewer, Peter Bryan, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brewster, Zedich, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brice, James, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Bright, Francis, 1877-1878 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Britton, Jonathan, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brooks, John T., 1860 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, David, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, John, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, Neil, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, Oliver, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Brown, [_], 1856 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Burnley, Garland, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Burroughs, George, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Burton, May, 1781 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Burton, Thomas, 1853-1859 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Butler, Lawrence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Revolutionary War - Cabell-Christian (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Cabell, Samuel Jordan, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Cammac, John, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Callis, William O., 1872 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Campbell, Richard, 1838, 1870-1871 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Campbell, William, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carden, Edward, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carlton, Lewis, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carter, Edward, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carter, John, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Carter, Thomas, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Catlett, Thomas, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Cave, William, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Cerney, Aaron, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Chambers, James, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Cheatham, James, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Chesher, John, 1858 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Chewning, Robert, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Child, [_], 1860 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Chilton, Andrew, 1838, 1852, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Christian, William, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Christian, Nicholas, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Revolutionary War - Clark-Cunningham (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clark, James, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clark, John, 1832 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clark, John, 1831, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clarke, Spencer, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Claiborne, Buller, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clements, Thomas, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clough, George, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clough, John, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Clough, Richard, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cochran, James, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cochran, Samuel, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cole, John, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cole, William, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cooper, William, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Corbett, John, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cottrell, William, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cox, Bartlett, 1848-1853 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Crawford, John, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Crawley, Samuel, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Crockett, Joseph, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cummings, George, 1854-1855 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cunningham, Nathaniel, 1853-1854 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Revolutionary War - Dance-Devane (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Dance, Etheldred, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Dandridge, John, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Darden, John, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Davis, John, 1853, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Davis, William, 1855, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Davis, William, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Davis, William, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Dener, George Frederick, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - DeRussey, Thomas, 1838, 1851-1852 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Devane, A. J., 1856 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Devane, James, 1851 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Revolutionary War - Dodson-Dudley (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dodson, George, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Doggett, George, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Donovan, Matthew, 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Downs, Thomas, 1851-1852 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dudley, Banks, 1851, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dudley, Henry, 1881 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dudley, James, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Revolutionary War - E (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Eanes, Arthur, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Eanes, William, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Ellis, Stephen, 1845-1854 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Epps, Peter, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Eaton, William, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Elliott, George, 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Elliott, William, 1852-1855 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Ellis, Abraham, 1851-1854 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Emmerson, John, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Revolutionary War - Falwell-Fleming (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Falwell, James, 1842, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fawcett, Obediah, 1852-1853 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fear, Jacob, 1856 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Ferguson, Francis, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Ferrier, Robert, 1857 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fleming, John, 1857-May 1858 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fleming, John, May 1858-1859 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fleming, John, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Fleming, Robert, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary War - Flippen-Funk (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Flippen, Robert, 1855-1856 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Fooshee, John, 1851 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Foster, Cosby, 1871 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Foster, James, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Foster, Peter, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Fountain, Solomon, 1853 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Fowkes, John, 1870-1878 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Frasher, Frederick, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Frazier, William E., 1851-1852 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Funk, Henry, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary War - Garner-Gill (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Garner, Benjamin, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Gates, Horatio, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Gatewood, Richard, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Gentry, James, 1859 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - George, William, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Gibbs, Churchill, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Gill, Mitchell, 1854 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary War - Gilliam (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Gilliam, John, 1855, 1876-1877 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Gilliam, John, January-February 1878 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Gilliam, John, March 1878-July 1878 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Revolutionary War - Gilliam-Goins (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Gilliam, John, September 1878-1880 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Glenn, William, 1852-1857 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Goff, Job, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Goins, Johnson, 1858 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Revolutionary War - Goodall (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Goodall, John, 1773-1837 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Goodall, John, 1784, 1804 (Box 34a, Folder 1)
      - Goodall, John, 1844-1845 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Goodall, John, 1852-1858 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Revolutionary War - Goodall (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Goodall, John, 1859-1878 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Goodall, John, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Goodall, John, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Revolutionary War - Goodson-Gray (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Goodson, Thomas, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Goodson, Thomas, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Gouldin, Jesse, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Gouldin, John, 1852-1856 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Grant, Daniel, 1855 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Gray, James, 1833-1852, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Revolutionary War - Greenway-Gregory (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Greenway, George, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Gregory, John, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Gregory, John, 1877-1880 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Gregory, William, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Revolutionary War - Griffin-Gunnell (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Griffin, Obediah, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Grymes, William, 1871, 1877 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Gunnell, William, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Revolutionary War - Halbert-Hixon (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Halbert, William, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hall, John, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hamilton, James, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hancock: Bennet, Daniel and Abram, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Handy, George, 1871-1872 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hardyman, John, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Harper, James, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Harrison, Charles, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Harris, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Harvey, Thomas, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hatcher, John, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hawes, William, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hawkins, Joseph, 1811 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hicks, Benjamin, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hill, Thomas, 1837-1860 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Hixon, James, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary War - Hobbs-Hutton (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hobbs, Thomas, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hockaday, John, 1838-1857 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Holman, Christian, 1876 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Holt, James, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hooper, James, 1854, 1866 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hopkins, [_] n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Howard, Robert, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Howe, James, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hubbard, Thomas, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hudson, John, 1854, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hundley, Nekemiah, 1836, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hunter, Moses, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Hutton, Henry, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary War - J (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jackson, John, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jeffries, Joseph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jernigan, George, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jews, America 1877 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnson, Benjamin, 1861-1872 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnson, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnson, John B., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnson, Obediah, 1852-1853 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnston, George, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Johnston, Peter, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, Henry, 1852-1853 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, James, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, John, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, John Paul, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, Joseph, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jones, Lewis, 1845 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jordan, James, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Jouitt, Matthew, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary War - K (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kemplin, William, 1849-1866 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kenley, Benjamin, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kennen, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kent, Jesse, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kelly, Thaddy, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kelly, Roger, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Keyser, Jacob, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kimplin, William, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kincannon, George, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - King, Valentine, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Kirtley, Elijah, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Revolutionary War - Lacy-Lehee (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lacy, Stephen, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lambert, George, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lane, John, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Larrow, Peter, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lavender, William, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lawson, Robert, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Leake, William, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lee, James, 1856-1857 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Lehee, Jeremiah, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Revolutionary War - Lewis-Lucas (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Abraham, 1860, 1873 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Addison, 1881-1882 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Charles, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Ruel, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Thomas, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lewis, Warner, 1852-1855, 1878-1882 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lightfoot, Philip, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lightfoot, William, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lipscomb, Bernard, 1797 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - lockett, Edmund, 1852-1853 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Long, Ware, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lovell, Robert, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Lucas, John, 1836-1852 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Revolutionary War - McGehee-Miller (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - McGehee, Joseph, 1857-1858 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - McNichol, John, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Magill, Charles, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Malone, John, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Markham, Bernard, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Martin, Joseph, 1832, 1853-1856 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Mason, David, 187- (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Massie, Thomas, 1854 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Maupin, Thomas, 1859 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Maxey, John, 1856 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Maxwell, James, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Meadow, Francis, 185- (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Miles, William, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Miller, James, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Miller, William Heath, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Revolutionary War - Milliner-Munford (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Milliner, Robert, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Mills, George, 1852 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Mitchell, John H., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Monday, Edward, 1853 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Moore, Alexander, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Morgan, Daniel, 1783 and n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Mosby, John and Littleberry, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Moss, Henry, 1855 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Mountjoy, Alvin, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Munford, Edward, 1856-1857 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Revolutionary War - N (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Nancarrow, John, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Nelson, [_] 1851 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Neville, Presley, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Newell, William, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Norvell, Aquilla, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Nutter, Christopher, 1854-1856 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Revolutionary War - O (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Odell, Jeremiah, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Oliver, William, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - O'Neal, Ferdinand, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - O'Neal, John, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Revolutionary War - Pace-Payne (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Pace, Newsum, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Painter, Henry, 1854-1866 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Pannill, David, 1853-1857 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Parham, William, 1852-1856 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Patterson, Thomas, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Payne, Benjamin D., 1851 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Payne, Joseph, 1854-1855 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Payne, William, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Revolutionary War - Peeples-Pollard (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Peeples, Abner, 1854 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Peers, Valentine, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Perkinson, Thomas, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Perry, John, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Peters, James, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Pettus, Thomas and John, 1853-1854 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Philips, Edward, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Phillips, Mourning, 1853-1854 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Pollard, Benjamin, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Pollard, Robert, 1855, 1858 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Revolutionary War - Porter-Price (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Porter, Thomas, 1790-1851 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Porter, Thomas, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Powell, Abraham, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Powell, Francis, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Powell, Seymour, 1850 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Price, Barrett, 1791-1794, 1851-1852 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Revolutionary War - Q and R (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Quarles, [_], 1878 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ralph, Ephraim, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ramsbottam, Isaac, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ramsey, George, 1856 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ransome, Thomas, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Read, Edmund, 1845-1847 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Reade, Isaac, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Roane, Christopher, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Roberts, James, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Roberts, William, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Robinson, Littlebury and James, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Rogers, Bowling, 1854, 1866 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Rogers, Joseph, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Rudolph, Michael, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Ruffin, Thomas, 1871-1875 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Russell, William, 1871 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Revolutionary War - Samuel-Singleton (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Samuel, Gary, 1854 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Sampson, Philip, 1881 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Saunders, Celey, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Saunders, Richard, 1855, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Savage, Joseph R., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Scott, George, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Scott, John B., 1855, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Sears, Thomas, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Seigle, Frederick, 1877 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Shearer, John, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Singleton, Joshua, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Revolutionary War - Slaughter-Smith (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Slaughter, John, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Sledge, Amos, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Charles, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Daniel, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, John, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Joseph, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Matthew, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Smith, Robert, 1852 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Revolutionary War - Snead-Spears (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Snead, Robert, 1853 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Snelson, Nathaniel, 1852-1856 (Box 4, Folder 7)